Daniel Varney Thompson
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Writings, 1907-1970s, Series 4:; (Boxes 6-9; 2.85 linear ft.)
  - By Other Authors, 1907-1967, 4.3:
    - Thompson, Cecile de Luze. Notes on Weaving Patterns (with diagrams), 1931 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Thompson, Grace R. Diary [typescript copy], summer 1907 and summer 1908 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Thompson, Randall. "Say Ye to the Righteous" (music score inscribed to Dan and Cecily), 1935 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Trotta, Geri. "Buenos Aires: Europe I South America," undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Artwork, 1923-1934, Series 5:; (Box 9, OV package 13; 5 folders)
  This series includes drawings, prints, watercolors, and an oil painting. A small number of drawings, prints and a sketchbook containing pencil sketches and watercolors are by Daniel V. Thompson.
  Artwork is arranged alphabetically by artist.
  - McKean, Mary Sargent. Drawing and Watercolors, 1934, undated, (see also: OV 13) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Thompson, Daniel Varney. Drawings, Prints, and Sketchbook, 1923, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
  - Winslow, Henry. Print, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - McKean, Mary Sargent [signed Sargent]. Oil Painting, undated (Box OV 13)
- Printed Material, 1917-1979, Series 6:; (Box 9; 0.75 linear ft.)
  Items of particular interest are concert programs and articles about/mentioning noted American composer Randall Thompson, the older brother of Daniel Varney Thompson, and material concerning Daniel Varney Thompson and the Thompson Family. Also included is Le memorie di un pittore di quadric antichi, a book by Inicio Federico Joni under whom Thompson studied medieval and Renaissance painting techniques while in Italy in 1923.
  A significant amount of additional printed material can be found in the Subject Files (Series 3).
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries. Printed material is categorized by record type with each folder arranged chronologically.
  6.1: By Daniel Varney Thompson, 1926-1971
  6.2: By Other Authors, 1917-1979
  - By Daniel Varney Thompson, 1926-1971, 6.1:
    - Articles, 1926-1969 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Book Reviews, 1933, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Letters to Editors, 1967-1971 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous Items, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Poem, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - By Other Authors, 1924-1974, 6.2:
    - About/Mentioning Daniel Varney Thompson (Box 9)
      - Articles, 1924-1967, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Biographical Notes, circa 1950-1979, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Letterheads and Business Cards, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Membership Lists, 1936-1964, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Reviews and Advertisements of Books by Thompson, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - About/Mentioning Randall Thompson (Box 9)
      - Articles, 1939-1974, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Concert Programs, 1939-1974 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - About/Mentioning Thompson Family, 1926-1970, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Articles (Box 9)
      - Art, History Medieval Studies, Science and Technology, 1936-1968, undated, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 25-28)
      - Food and Garden, 1963-1967, undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1962-1973, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Books (Box 9)
      - L'arte della seta in Firenze by Girolamo Gargiolli (photocopy), undated, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - The Göttingen Model Book, edited by Helmut Lehmann-Haupt (photocopy), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Die Herstellung des Blattmetalls in Altertum und Neuzeit by Wilhelm Theobald, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Le memorie di un pittore di quadric antichi by Inicio Federico Joni, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Items, 1935-1964, undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Periodicals - Mathematical Pie (Nos. 1-53), 1950-1967 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Printing Samples (Carl Purington Rollins, Daniel Varney Thompson, and others), 1917-1955, undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Photographs, circa 1900-1972, Series 7:; (Box 10; 0.4 linear ft.)
  Photographs are of artwork, people, places and miscellaneous subjects. The majority of photographs of people are of Daniel V. Thompson and family members. Other individuals portrayed are Edward Forbes with colleagues and family at Villa Curonia, Shaw and Margaret Sargent McKean, and a number of unidentified people. Some Subject Files (Series 3) also include photographs.
  The series is arranged as 5 subseries. Images of artwork are arranged by artist.
  7.1: Artwork, 1906-circa 1941
  7.2: People, circa 1900-1969
  7.3: Places, 1923-1972
  7.4: Miscellaneous Subjects, 1929-1969
  7.5: Negative and Transparency, undated
  - Artwork, 1906-circa 1941, 7.1:
    - Greaves, T. A., undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Lyon, Robert, circa 1941 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - McKean, Margaret Sargent, 1937, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Taylor, Edwin C., 1933 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Thompson, Daniel Varney, Jr., circa 1939, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified, 1906-1925, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - People, circa 1900-1969, 7.2:
    - Thompson, Cecile de Luze Simonds, 1903-1936 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Thompson, Daniel Varney (Box 10)
      - Portraits, 1903-1972 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - With Cecile and their Children, 1931-1944 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - With Colleagues and Friends, 1919-1968 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Family (Box 10)
      - Thompson Family (group shots with and without Daniel Varney Thompson), 1900-circa 1938, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Thompson, Daniel Varney, Sr. [father], 19th century (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Thompson, Frederick Lincoln [uncle], circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Thompson, John Ireland [son] and Anthea [daughter], 1939-circa 1946 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Thompson, William Ladd [relationship unknown], undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Varney, D. A. [probably uncle or grandfather], 19th century (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Friends (Box 10)
      - Forbes, Edward and Margaret with Others (at Villa Curonia, Florence), 1923 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - McKean, Margaret Sargent, Shaw, and Family, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Other Individuals, 1906-1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Places, 1923-1972, 7.3:
    - China, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Gardens, 1956-1965 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Greenhouses, 1966, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Houses, 1964, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Italy, 1923 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Storeroom, Daniel Varney, Ltd., 1943 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Unidentified (landscapes; buildings), undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1929-1969, 7.4:
    - Architectural Models of Yale University Art Gallery (proposed extension), undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Automobiles, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Consulting Projects, circa 1940s, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Dogs, 1929-1966 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Flowers, 1966-1969, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Scientific Data, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Negative and Transparency, undated, 7.5:
    - Negative (Artwork by Margaret Sargent McKean), undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Color Transparency (Consulting Project), undated (Box 10, Folder 34)